ButterflyLens brings Australia’s rebuilt ALA baseline
into one inspectable evidence workspace.
The catalogue has 463 accepted butterfly species. The public occurrence layer stays withheld
while provider rights remain unresolved—that boundary is intentional.
Flickr is the live discovery stream,
not a biodiversity record.
This replay has the deterministic request plan, but no completed immutable result.
Active partial outputs are never substituted into the demo.
Governed candidates are designed to flow
through the M5 pipeline.
No authenticated heartbeat, committed batch, or model fingerprint is attached.
YOLOE and BioCLIP remain unfinished, so progress is not invented.
Community expertise enters through blind review. Without enough visible evidence,
I choose “Can’t tell” rather than force an identity.
Only after the draft is locked do source details appear.
This changes local demo state; it submits nothing and verifies no species.
The map does not change from one local draft.
A public update needs independent review, rights and sensitivity checks,
and a fingerprinted committed artifact.
Stronger evidence requires repeated, independent reviewers
and an explicit consensus policy.
This replay stores no community review or identity.
Unavailable totals stay unavailable; model or majority agreement is not truth.
Quality needs a representative audit,
not a convenient sample.
Precision and its interval are unavailable—not zero.
The 2,906 valid decodes are diagnostics; zero species are human-verified here.
Bounded model is the bounded live analyst target. It explains deterministic evidence
through read-only tools and never identifies from memory.
For judging, this stored replay preserves the reference-review queue,
exact citations, and tool output. The footer proves no model ran here.
Geographic impact will compare reviewed imagery
with the ALA baseline at safe resolution.
No selectable impact cell is released yet.
Withheld coverage does not mean biological absence.
Export is governed too. ButterflyLens exposes
the release contract, not a pretend download.
Unreviewed Flickr candidates can never enter
the final occurrence archive.
Codex built and tested the product
and its provenance.
It supplied no butterfly identity,
community vote, or scientific ground truth.