ButterflyLens starts with the authoritative rebuilt ALA baseline:
236,897 selected occurrence-evidence rows.
The Submitted public map exposes 213,310 map-eligible rows across 630 blue H3 cells.
It is a selected baseline, not complete biological truth.
Flickr is the live discovery stream,
not a biodiversity record.
This replay has the deterministic request plan, but no completed immutable result.
Active partial outputs are never substituted into the demo.
Governed candidates are designed to flow
through the M5 pipeline.
No authenticated heartbeat, committed batch, or model fingerprint is attached.
YOLOE and BioCLIP remain unfinished, so progress is not invented.
Community expertise enters through blind review. Without enough visible evidence,
I choose “Can’t tell” rather than force an identity.
Only after the draft is locked do source details appear.
This changes local demo state; it submits nothing and verifies no species.
One local draft cannot update this map. H3 cell 838c23fffffffff
links 224 ALA baseline rows to fingerprinted evidence.
The source sample is coordinate-free. A future Flickr or review layer
needs its own committed, rights-cleared evidence.
Stronger evidence requires repeated, independent reviewers
and an explicit consensus policy.
This replay stores no community review or identity.
Unavailable totals stay unavailable; model or majority agreement is not truth.
Quality needs a representative audit,
not a convenient sample.
Precision and its interval are unavailable—not zero.
The 2,906 valid decodes are diagnostics; zero species are human-verified here.
GPT-5.6 is the bounded live analyst target. It explains deterministic evidence
through read-only tools and never identifies from memory.
The model-free replay cites the ALA aggregate, refuses an unsupported Flickr difference,
and preserves its tool trace. The footer proves no model ran here.
The Submitted map drills into state, IBRA,
LGA, and H3 counts.
Cross-source impact awaits an immutable Flickr layer.
Missing coverage is not biological absence.
Export is governed too. ButterflyLens exposes
the release contract, not a pretend download.
Unreviewed Flickr candidates can never enter
the final occurrence archive.
Codex built and tested the product
and its provenance.
It supplied no butterfly identity,
community vote, or scientific ground truth.